{
  "theme": [
    {
      "Questions": [
        {
          "Question": "Who is the author of the Harry Potter series?",
          "TrueAnswer": "J.K. Rowling",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Suzanne Collins",
            "Veronica Roth",
            "Cassandra Clare"
          ],
          "Explanation": "J.K. Rowling wrote the Harry Potter series, which consists of seven fantasy novels, published between 1997 and 2007."
        },
        {
          "Question": "In 'The Hunger Games,' what is the name of the protagonist?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Katniss Everdeen",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Tris Prior",
            "Bella Swan",
            "Hermione Granger"
          ],
          "Explanation": "'The Hunger Games' centers on Katniss Everdeen, who volunteers to take her sister's place in a televised fight to the death."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which YA book series was authored by Rick Riordan?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Percy Jackson & the Olympians",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Divergent",
            "The Mortal Instruments",
            "The Maze Runner"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Rick Riordan is known for writing the 'Percy Jackson & the Olympians' series, widely popular for its modernized portrayal of Greek mythology."
        },
        {
          "Question": "What is the genre of 'The Fault in Our Stars' by John Green?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Young Adult Contemporary",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Science Fiction",
            "Fantasy",
            "Historical Fiction"
          ],
          "Explanation": "'The Fault in Our Stars' is a young adult contemporary novel that deals with themes of love, illness, and mortality."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which character narrates 'The Perks of Being a Wallflower'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Charlie",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Katniss",
            "Percy",
            "Hazel"
          ],
          "Explanation": "'The Perks of Being a Wallflower' is a coming-of-age novel written as a series of letters from Charlie to an anonymous recipient."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Who wrote the 'Divergent' series?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Veronica Roth",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Stephenie Meyer",
            "Suzanne Collins",
            "Tahereh Mafi"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Veronica Roth authored the 'Divergent' series, set in a dystopian society where individuals are divided based on their personalities."
        },
        {
          "Question": "What is the title of the first book in the 'A Court of Thorns and Roses' series?",
          "TrueAnswer": "A Court of Thorns and Roses",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Throne of Glass",
            "Cinder",
            "Red Queen"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The first book in the 'A Court of Thorns and Roses' series, written by Sarah J. Maas, shares its title with the series."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which of these series was written by Cassandra Clare?",
          "TrueAnswer": "The Mortal Instruments",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Legend",
            "Shatter Me",
            "Vampire Academy"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Cassandra Clare penned 'The Mortal Instruments' series, comprised of six novels in the urban fantasy genre."
        },
        {
          "Question": "In 'The Maze Runner,' what is the name of the main protagonist?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Thomas",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Katniss",
            "Tris",
            "Peeta"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Thomas is the main character in 'The Maze Runner' series, a young adult dystopian science fiction novel by James Dashner."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Who is the author of 'The Book Thief'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Markus Zusak",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Kiera Cass",
            "Laini Taylor",
            "Ransom Riggs"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Markus Zusak penned 'The Book Thief,' set in Nazi Germany and narrated by Death, presenting a unique perspective on war and literature."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which series is known for the line, 'Do you want a sugar cube?'",
          "TrueAnswer": "The Hunger Games",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Twilight",
            "The Selection",
            "Lord of the Rings"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The line 'Do you want a sugar cube?' is from 'The Hunger Games' series, where it signifies a form of care and kindness amidst brutal circumstances."
        },
        {
          "Question": "What is the capital city in 'The Selection' series by Kiera Cass?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Ilingen",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Orya",
            "Anklene",
            "Kenadi"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The capital city in 'The Selection' series is known as Ilingen, where much of the political and romantic drama unfolds."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Who wrote 'The Infernal Devices' trilogy?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Cassandra Clare",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Suzanne Collins",
            "Veronica Roth",
            "Marie Lu"
          ],
          "Explanation": "'The Infernal Devices' trilogy is authored by Cassandra Clare, set in the same world as 'The Mortal Instruments' series."
        },
        {
          "Question": "What is the genre of the 'Throne of Glass' series by Sarah J. Maas?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Young Adult Fantasy",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Historical Fiction",
            "Science Fiction",
            "Contemporary"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The 'Throne of Glass' series is a young adult fantasy saga with intricate world-building and a strong, complex protagonist."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Who is the author of 'The Lunar Chronicles' series?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Marissa Meyer",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Tahereh Mafi",
            "Sarah J. Maas",
            "Kiera Cass"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Marissa Meyer created 'The Lunar Chronicles,' a futuristic retelling of classic fairytales with a science fiction twist."
        },
        {
          "Question": "In 'Miss Peregrine's Home for Peculiar Children,' what is Jake's peculiar ability?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Seeing Hollowgasts",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Invisibility",
            "Teleportation",
            "Mind Reading"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Jake's peculiar ability in 'Miss Peregrine's Home for Peculiar Children' is the power to see and identify Hollowgasts, monstrous beings that threaten the peculiar children."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Who is the author of the 'Shatter Me' series?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Tahereh Mafi",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Marie Lu",
            "Laini Taylor",
            "Stephanie Garber"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Tahereh Mafi is the author of the 'Shatter Me' series, featuring a unique writing style and a plot filled with romance, action, and intrigue."
        },
        {
          "Question": "What is the title of the first book in the 'Red Queen' series?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Red Queen",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Falling Kingdoms",
            "The Selection",
            "Graceling"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The first book in the 'Red Queen' series, written by Victoria Aveyard, shares its title with the series and introduces the world of Reds and Silvers."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Who is the author of the 'Legend' trilogy?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Marie Lu",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Diana Gabaldon",
            "Ally Condie",
            "Livia Blackburne"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Marie Lu is the author of the 'Legend' trilogy, known for its dystopian, science fiction world and the characters June and Day."
        },
        {
          "Question": "What is the nickname of the female protagonist in 'The Lunar Chronicles'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Cinder",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Kai",
            "Scarlet",
            "Winter"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The nickname of the female protagonist in 'The Lunar Chronicles' is Cinder, derived from her role as a talented mechanic and her connection to the classic fairytale character."
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}